I'm calling this the renaissance of
development because if you didn't do VIP
coding, just setting up the the build
environment can already take you couple
of days to to make that work. Being a
more senior developer, it makes me
definitely be more productive. I could
have never created the UI that it has
produced for me. The project I've now
done in more or less 5 weeks now, it
would have taken me definitely three
people 6 months without doing VIP
coding. But you still need some senior
developers guiding this because if you
don't, you're going to run into
problems.
[Music]
For example, like Angular has guard uh
rules. So we have routing and you can
put guards in front of the routing. If
you don't know that concept, you're
going to give access to certain pages u
as a junior or or non techy guy uh
without knowing or you might actually
expose uh API keys or really security
issues and that's why I've also did
certain exercises where I said like to
close code hey you're a white white hat
hacker try to hack my system and it
actually goes through your codes goes to
your website and tries to hack your
system and those are really valuable
exercises because it will actually
highlight ah I was able to see the admin
page without being logged in okay well
fix it you know look at it and go deeper
or I did another exercise where I went I
went where I went like okay we have
3,000 unique users during DevOps Belgium
uh how will the system scale how will be
performed where are the bottlenecks and
it does this exercise where it really
then goes like Well, your firebased
functions you should have better memory
or more memory you need to allow more
instances etc. So having these other
type of discussions which are not so
much development oriented but more
devops oriented is definitely also a
step you need to do within that process.
>> I'd love to break that down a little
further. We there's a couple of things
there that I'd love to talk through. The
first one is you kind of you kind of
alluded to the fact that you need those
senior developers or or people who
really understand have that sympathy of
what is being built, what's happening to
to review essentially or or to make sure
to validate that what is being created
um is actually correct. It's the right
way of doing things. It's the right
implementation so to speak. an amount of
that can be done, I guess, with with
things like tests and things like that.
Um, how how much did you do a lot of
those reviews versus what it sounds like
allowed the the LLMs or different LLMs
to kind of like jump in and do those
reviews for you? Were you comfortable if
you just let DeepSeek or something else
come through and say, "Tell me if this
is okay and I'll trust you." Where was
your limit?
>> No, I was not fully 100% comfortable for
sure. Um, just this morning I actually
found another bug in the deployed
application now because it's already
being used now by by hundreds hundreds
of people uh for DevOps Belgium. And so
I did a a refactoring using prompting
where the speaker can actually edit his
pictures which are identified from
Flickr using face recognition and he or
she can decide which picture he wants to
show on his speaker profile. And so that
worked, but it actually broke a feature
where the pictures are not shown anymore
uh on the public page. And I went like
what happened? And so I could not have I
mean I could have only fixed that or
anticipated that with using uh end to
end uh testing using Cypress. I've
chosen Cyprus, but I had no test for
that specific scenario. So it basically
broke something in production and where
I went like but to be honest this can
happen also in normal teams without
doing vi coding right I mean this is
reality it these things do happen um so
my target is I would love to get a 80%
coverage with the unit tests I would
love to have more end toend testing as
well but that just takes still a lot of
effort even if it's just prompting but
it would increase my confidence that
yeah if I do deploy it and I have those
type of coverages um it it would
increase my confidence to to to move
forward. Um, so I think those are
definitely critical to to have um
without you're just walking in a dark
room and you're going to hit your head
against the wall for sure, right? Uh so
I think test driven or or just unit
testing, integration testing um is is
becoming more and more important to make
sure to enforce the specs that you've
defined and I think that collaboration
will will be a success. Comi